Objective: Senior Software Tester Automation Engineer - QA

Carlos Eduardo de Oliveira

Phone: +351 911 956 381 email: carloseduardo1984@gmail

GitHub: https://github.com/carloseduardo1984 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/carlosoliveira1984/

Summary



I am a trilingual quality control engineer (English, Spanish and Portuguese) with more than 20 years of experience in quality (QLT+A2), with 10 years focused on IT and software projects, and services. And more than 500 technological projects with my collaborations. A professional in a process focused on quality, SDLC, GxP, Scale Agile, and Scrum. With experience with the tools: JIRA, Zephyr, Xray, HP-ALM, SAP Solution Manager, Cucumber, Cypress, Robot Framework, Selenium WebDriver, Jest, Postman, Newman, GitHub Actions, Jenkins, and a lot of software projects since locals (small) until cross regions approach (global), under QA Agile Test practices and Scrum methodologies.

Professional Experience: 21 Years

Professional Experience: Swiss Post – IT Lisbon Campus – Transport Finance Logistics areas		
Period:	Apr-2023 to Today	
Position:	Senior Tester Engineer QA Mentor	
Level of intervention:	Schlot rester Engineer on eastorn elearance & transport respects	
Roles:	SQA, Tester Engineer, Dev Team member, Scrum member, and QA Mentor	
Projects:	3 Custom Clearance cross regions projects & 1 Transport project	
Project and Technologies:	Test Automations Developments for API and Frontend with Robot Framework, Selenium & Python, Jenkins, GitHub Actions, Bitbucket, Git, Jira, Xray, Confluence, Scrum, and Kanban.	
Tasks:	Mapping and guidance on manual and automated regression test strategy and plan. Review of requirements acceptance criteria mapped to JIRA user stories. Development and reviews of scripts to define test automation requirements in Xray JIRA, development of automated tests with Robot framework, and CICD integrated into DEV and QA environment.	
Professional Experience: Aubay Portugal Consultant - Client Diconium VW Group - Automobilist area		
Period:	Mar-2022 to Apr-2023	

Professional Experience: Aubay Portugal Consultant - Client Diconium VW Group - Automobilist area		
Period:	Mar-2022 to Apr-2023	
Position:	Senior Automation Tester	
Level of intervention:	Senior Tester Engineer (100% allocated)	
Roles:	SQA, Tester Engineer, Dev Team member, Scrum member.	
Projects:	Ecommerce AI platform for VW, Audi, Cupra, Seat, and Skoda (Automobile companies)	
Project and Technologies:	Test Automations Developments for API and Frontend with Cucumber (BDD), Cypress (JavaScript, NodeJS, Mocha), GitHub Actions, Git, Jira, Xray, Confluence, Scrum, and Kanban.	

Technologies:	restriction at the section in the section with education (DDD), express (savaseript, reduces),	
reciliologies.	Mocha), GitHub Actions, Git, Jira, Xray, Confluence, Scrum, and Kanban.	

Professional Experience: TCS Consultant	- Client Citibank LATAM - Finance	Bank area

	*
Period:	Senior Tester Engineer (100% allocated)
Position:	SQA, Tester Automation Engineer, Dev Team member, Scrum member.
Level of intervention:	Ecommerce AI platform for VW, Audi, Cupra, Seat, and Skoda (Automobile companies)
Roles:	Test Automations Developments for API and Frontend with Cucumber (BDD), framework with Selenium & JavaScript (NodeJS, Mocha), GitHub Actions, Git, Jira, Xray, Confluence, Scrum, and Kanban.
Project and Technologies:	Test Automations Developments for Frontend with Selenium Web driver (Java8, Junit, TestNG, HTML Reports, CSV Key-Driven), Cucumber (BDD, Cucumber reports), Cypress (JavaScript, NodeJS, Mocha), GitHub Actions, Git, Jira, Xray, Zephyr, Confluence, Scrum, and Kanban.

Professional Experience: Infosys Consultant - Client Global Account Johnson & Johnson - Medical | Finance | Automation | E-commerce areas

Period: 02-May-2019 to 07-Jun-2021

Position: Software Quality Assurance and Agile Coach for Global Projects (18 Go-Lives)

Level of External Consultant for Software Test and Software Quality Assurance (100% allocated but between 3 intervention:

or 4 projects at the same time)

Roles: QA Engineer, Tester Coach, Agile Coach, and Software Consultant

18 Go-lives, 8 Agile and 4 Waterfalls, and 6 Hybrids. (Heath Care, Medical, Consumer, HR, Finance) Projects:

- JJCC Pharma (Ecommerce) Agile Project
- Workday (HR Platform) Waterfall Project
- 2 with SAP (Abbott LATAM & EMA) Hybrid Project
- 3 with Celonis (Data Analytics solution for J&J Heath Care NAM, Latam & ASPAC) Hybrid Project
- 4 Seasons (SAP Finance Export tool for J&J LATAM) Agile Project
- Plant Cockpit (Automation Data Analytics for J&J Consumer LATAM) Agile Project
- Power Informatica (ETL Migration for J&J Consumer LATAM) Waterfall Project
- Cognos Project (J&J Customer control database) Medical) Hybrid Project
- BIDs Salesforce Implementation (J&J Consumer LATAM) Agile Project
- C4G Single Sign-On (J&J Heath Care Global Integration with SAP, SalesForce & Datalake) Global Safe Agile Project
- Kronos Chichen Itza (J&J HR Latam Platform solution for Workday) Agile Project
- Asset Performance Automation (Data Analytics Interface for J&J Consumer LATAM)
- JJVC Market Place (J&J Consumer LATAM Ecommerce Platform) Agile Project
- JJCC Pharma (J&J Latam Ecommerce Platform) Agile Project
- JJCC PAC (J&J North America Logistics Consumer Ecommerce) Waterfall Project

Technologies:

Manual Adhocs with JIRA Xray and Zephyr, Manual Tests with HP-ALM, SAP Solution Manager for Test tracking, Salesforce Manual Tests, RPAs with UIPath, Scrum and Kanban ceremonies, SDLC documentation as SQA, Test Plan Developments, Test Strategies, Test Coaching, Trainer about Xray, HP-ALM Tests, and SDLC QA best practices for test validations. PowerBI QA Metrics development.

Professional Experience: Client CEO Consultoria - Project SQA Consultant - Automation | E-Commerce areas

Period: 16-Fev-2012 to 27-Apr-2019

Position: **QA Engineer Consultant**

Level of Technical Analyst | Developer

intervention: Roles:

QA Engineer, Software and Hardware Developer Consultant

Projects: 212 Go-lives, 12 Agile and 200 Waterfalls, all in LATAM area.

Professional Experience: Electronics Engineering Projects - MCM, Denso, NICE, Tamura clients

14-Jan-2003 to Fev-2012 Period:

Roles: QA Automation & Electronics Engineer Consultant, Hardware Product Consultant

Projects: 1215 Product Go-lives, 200 Project reviews, and 50 client visits, all in LATAM area.

Objective: Senior Software Tester Automation Engineer - QA

Skills		
Tool / Technology	Duration (years)	Expertise Level
QA and Tester Engineering	21	Expert
Agile / Scrum Methodologies	9	Senior
Jira / Confluence – Project Management	9	Senior
Xray & Zephyr Test Management & Execution Tools (Jira Test Plugin)	8	Senior
HP-ALM Tools - Reviewer & Tester	3	Intermediated
Excel & MS Power BI – for QA Business Analysis for Project Metrics	10	Senior
Test Automations with Cypress & Python with Selenium	4	Senior
JavaScript / Java Tester Automation	5	Senior

Academic Background			
Graduation	Specialization	Institution	GraduationDate
MBA	Strategic Management and Innovation	Unis University Center	Dec-2018
University	Automation and Control Engineer	Una University Center	Aug-2015
Post-Graduation	Electronic Systems and Automation	Inatel - University	Aug-2013
Graduation	Industrial Automation Bachelor	Itajuba University Center	Dec-2009

Certifications		
Certification	Provider	Date
Certified Tester Foundation Level	bSTQB	Jun-2021
CTFL – Agile Tester	iSTQB	Aug-2021
Jira with Agile Mindset	Atlassian University	May-2020
International Scrum Master	Scrum Assembly.org	Apr-2019

Additional Training			
Training	Provider	Hours	Start Date
Test Automation – UI, Java, C#, Python, Cypress, Selenium, Mobile & Web	Test Automation University	135	2019 & 2021 & 2023
Leadership & Agile Projects & Project Management	iPed & Udemy & FGV Ead	110	2014 & 2017 & 2022
Time Management & Strategic Thinking	Harvard Manage Mentor	6	May-2020

More than 800 hours of technical trainings on topics related to Software Projects, Software development, and Software test automation

Languages			
Language	Global Level		
Portuguese	Native		
English	C1 = Advanced		
Spanish	B1 = Intermediate		
French & German	A1 = Basic		